Colin White

847-828-3885 201 Mission Street San Francisco, CA 94105

colin@abacus.ai
https://crwhite.ml

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am interested in automating, explaining, and de-biasing deep learning models, from both a theoretical and empirical lens. Much of my work involves designing innovative methods by drawing insights from large-scale studies and designing tools for better benchmarking of machine learning techniques.

EXPERIENCE

Abacus.AI, San Francisco, CA

Head of Research

Research Scientist

Oct. 2020 – Present

May 2019 – Oct. 2020

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D. in Computer Science Sep. 2014 – Dec. 2018

Advisor: Maria-Florina Balcan

Thesis committee: Avrim Blum, Anupam Gupta, Yury Makarychev, and David Woodruff

Amherst College, Amherst, MA

B.A. in Computer Science and Mathematics Sep. 2010 – May 2014

Graduated Summa Cum Laude

GPA: 3.76/4.0

SELECTED HONORS AND AWARDS

Top 10% of reviewers at ICML 2022	Jul. 2022
Top 10% of reviewers at ICLR 2022	Apr. 2022
Top 10% of reviewers at NeurIPS 2021	Dec. 2021
Top 10% of reviewers at ICML 2021	July 2021
Top 10% of reviewers at NeurIPS 2020	Dec. 2020
$2^{\rm nd}$ place at the CVPR NAS unseen data competition (77 submissions)	June 2021
National Defense Science & Engineering (NDSEG) Fellowship	Sep. 2014 – Dec. 2018
Amherst Memorial Fellowship	Sep. 2016 – Aug. 2017
John Woodruff Simpson Fellowship	Sep. 2014 – Aug. 2016
Post-Baccalaureate Summer Research Fellowship, Amherst College	Sep. 2014
Computer Science Prize (best thesis), Amherst College	May 2014
Henry F. Dunbar Award, Amherst College Swimming and Diving Team	May 2014

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

"k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience." With Maria-Florina Balcan and Nika Haghtalab. Transactions on Algorithms (TALG) 2020.

"Small dynamical heights for quadratic polynomials and rational functions." With Rob Benedetto, Ruqian Chen, Trevor Hyde, and Yordanka Kovacheva.

Experimental Mathematics, 2014.

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

"A Deeper Look at Zero-Cost Proxies for Lightweight NAS"

<u>Colin White</u>, Mikhail Khodak, Renbo Tu, Shital Shah, Sébastien Bubeck, Debadeepta Dey International Conference on Learning Representations Blog Post Track (ICLR Blog Post) 2022

"NAS-Bench-Suite: NAS Evaluation is (Now) Surprisingly Easy"

Yash Mehta*, Colin White*, Arber Zela, Arjun Krishnakumar, Guri Zabergja, Shakiba Moradian,

Mahmoud Safari, Kaicheng Yu, Frank Hutter

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.

"Synthetic Benchmarks for Scientific Research in Explainable Machine Learning"

Yang Liu*, Sujay Khandagale*, Colin White, Willie Neiswanger

Neural Information Processing Systems Datasets Track (NeurIPS Datasets), 2021.

"NAS-Bench-x11 and the Power of Learning Curves"

Shen Yan*, Colin White*, Yash Savani, Frank Hutter

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.

"How Powerful are Performance Predictors in Neural Architecture Search?"

Colin White, Arber Zela, Binxin Ru, Yang Liu, Frank Hutter.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.

"Exploring the Loss Landscape in Neural Architecture Search"

Colin White, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani.

Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2021.

"BANANAS: Bayesian Optimization with Neural Architectures for Neural Architecture Search."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Yash Savani.

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021.

"A Study on Encodings for Neural Architecture Search."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani.

Selected for spotlight presentation.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.

"Intra-Processing Methods for Debiasing Neural Networks."

Yash Savani, Colin White, Naveen Govindarajulu.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.

"Robust Communication-Optimal Distributed Clustering Algorithms."

With Pranjal Awasthi, Ainesh Bakshi, Maria-Florina Balcan, and David Woodruff.

International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP) 2019.

"Data-Driven Clustering via Parameterized Lloyd's Families."

With Maria-Florina Balcan and Travis Dick.

Selected for spotlight presentation.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2018.

"Learning-Theoretic Foundations of Algorithm Configuration for Combinatorial Partitioning Problems."

With Maria-Florina Balcan, Vaishnavh Nagarajan, and Ellen Vitercik.

Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) 2017.

"Data Driven Resource Allocation for Distributed Learning."

With Travis Dick, Mu Li, Krishna Pillutla, Maria-Florina Balcan, and Alex Smola.

International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS) 2017.

"Learning Combinatorial Functions from Pairwise Comparisons."

With Maria-Florina Balcan and Ellen Vitercik.

Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) 2016.

"k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience."

With Maria-Florina Balcan and Nika Haghtalab.

International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP) 2016.

"Lower Bounds in the Preprocessing and Query Phases of Routing Algorithms." Colin White.

European Symposium on Algorithms (ESA) 2015.

Theses

"New Aspects of Beyond Worst-Case Analysis."

Colin White.

Ph.D. Thesis, Carnegie Mellon University, 2018.

"Lower Bounds in the Preprocessing and Query Phases of Routing Algorithms."

Colin White.

Undergraduate Thesis, Amherst College, 2014.

Workshop Publications "Speeding up NAS with Adaptive Subset Selection"

Vishak Prasad, <u>Colin White</u>, Paarth Jain, Sibasis Nayak, Rishabh Iyer, Ganesh Ramakrishnan *AutoML-Conf Late-Breaking Workshop*, 2022.

"On the Generalizability and Predictability of Recommender Systems"

Duncan McElfresh*, Sujay Khandagale*, Jonathan Valverde*, John P. Dickerson, <u>Colin White AutoML-Conf Late-Breaking Workshop</u>, 2022.

"Synthetic Benchmarks for Scientific Research in Explainable Machine Learning"

Yang Liu*, Sujay Khandagale*, Colin White, Willie Neiswanger

ICML Workshop on Explainable AI, 2021.

"NAS-Bench-x11 and the Power of Learning Curves"

Shen Yan*, Colin White*, Yash Savani, Frank Hutter

CVPR Workshop on Neural Architecture Search, 2021.

"How Powerful are Performance Predictors in Neural Architecture Search?"

Colin White, Arber Zela, Binxin Ru, Yang Liu, Frank Hutter.

Selected as a contributed talk.

ICLR Workshop on Neural Architecture Search, 2021.

"A Study on Encodings for Neural Architecture Search."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani.

ICML Workshop on AutoML, 2020.

"Local Search is State of the Art for Neural Architecture Search Benchmarks."

Colin White, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani.

ICML Workshop on AutoML, 2020.

"Neural Architecture Search via Bayesian Optimization with a Neural Network Prior."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Yash Savani.

NeurIPS Workshop on Meta Learning, 2019.

"Deep Uncertainty Estimation for Model-based Neural Architecture Search."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Yash Savani.

NeurIPS Workshop on Bayesian Deep Learning, 2019.

"DECO: Debiasing through Compositional Optimization of Machine Learning Models."

Naveen Govindarajulu, Colin White.

NeurIPS Workshop on Robust AI in Financial Services, 2019.

"Differentiable Functions for Combining First-order Constraints with Deep Learning via Weighted Proof Tracing."

Naveen Govindarajulu, Colin White.

NeurIPS Workshop on Knowledge Representation to ML, 2019.

"Data Driven Resource Allocation for Distributed Learning."

With Travis Dick, Mu Li, Krishna Pillutla, Maria-Florina Balcan, and Alex Smola.

AAAI Workshop on Distributed Machine Learning, 2019.

"An Improved Parallel Iterative Algorithm for Stable Matching."

Colin White, Enyue Lu.

SuperComputing Poster, 2013.

Talks	Neural Architecture Search: The Next Frontier. Microsoft Research Redmond (virtual). Tutorial with Debadeepta Dey at AutoML-Conf 2022 in Baltimore, MD.	Aug. 2022 Jul. 2022
	Research Methodology. Judson University (virtual).	Nov. 2021
	AutoML: AI that Builds AI. PhxMobi Emerging Tech Festival (virtual).	Nov. 2021
	AutoML Panel Discussion. AutoML Seminar, ELLIS Berlin and Freiburg, Germany (virtual). NAS Workshop at ICLR 2021 (virtual).	Oct. 2021 May 2021
	Bananas, Encodings, and Local Search: Insights into Neural Architecture Search. AutoML Seminar, ELLIS Berlin and Freiburg, Germany (virtual).	Nov. 2020
	An Introduction to Neural Architecture Search. Abacus.AI workshop. Abacus.AI webinar. AICamp webinar.	Dec. 2019 Oct. 2020 Jul. 2019
	Data-Driven Clustering via Parameterized Lloyd's Families. Automated Algorithms Seminar at CMU.	May 2018
	Robust Communication-Optimal Distributed Clustering Algorithms. Theory Lunch Seminar at CMU.	Apr. 2017
	k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience. Simons Institute BWCA Workshop. Theory Lunch Seminar at CMU. Machine Learning Dept. Journal Club Class at CMU. Dagstuhl Workshop on Learning Theory.	Nov. 2016 Sep. 2016 Sep. 2016 Aug. 2015
Mentoring	LatinX AI (LXAI) Mentor for early-career researchers	2021 - present
	Deep Learning Indaba Mentor for early-career researchers	2022 - present
	Abacus.AI Mentor for early-career researchers	2019 - present
SERVICE	Program Chair for AutoML-Conf 2023	2023
	Local Chair and Area Chair for AutoML-Conf 2022	2022
	Organizer for the AutoML Workshop at ICML 2021	2021
	Journal reviewer for JMLR, TPAMI, TALG, Algorithmica	2015 – present
	Conference reviewer for NeurIPS, ICML, ICLR, AISTATS, AAAI, UAI, FOCS, STOC, SODA, ITCS	2015 – present
	Doctoral Review Committee Member, CMU A panel of graduate students and faculty who oversee the Ph.D. program	2015 - 2018
	Free CSD, a social organization for the Ph.D. department at CMU	2015 - 2018
	Theory Lunch Organizer, CMU	2016
	Ph.D. Admitted Students Open House Organizer, CMU	2016